在这个视频中，你将了解一种新的采样方法，它比我们迄今为止使用的DDPM高效10倍以上。
In this video, you'll learn about a new sampling method that is over 10 times   efficient than DDPM, which is what we've been using so far.
这种新方法叫做DDIM。
And this new method is called DDIM.
你的目标是想要更多的图片，并且快速得到它们。
So your goal is that you want more images, and you want them quickly.
但是到目前为止，采样速度很慢，因为涉及到很多时间步骤，
But sampling so far has been slow because, one, there are many time steps involved,
比如500个，有时甚至更多才能得到一个好的样本。
you know, 500, there are even more sometimes to get a good sample.
而且每个时间步骤都依赖于前一个。
And also each time step is dependent on the previous one.
它遵循一个马尔可夫链过程。
It follows a Markov chain process.
但幸运的是，有许多新的采样器来解决这个问题，因为这一直是扩散模型的一个长期问题。
But thankfully, there are many new samplers here to address this problem, since this has been a long standing problem with diffusion models.
你可以训练它们，它们可以创造出既多样又逼真的惊人美丽的图像，
It's that you can train them and they can create amazing, beautiful images that are both diverse and realistic,
但从它们那里得到结果的速度非常慢。
but it's so slow to get something out of them.
其中一种非常受欢迎的采样器叫做DDIM，即去噪扩散隐式模型，这只是论文的名字。
And one of these samplers that has been very popular is called DDIM, or Denoising Diffusion Implicit Models, which is just the name of the paper.
这篇论文是由Jiaming Song、Chenlin Meng和我的博士联合导师Stefano Ermon共同完成的。
And this paper was written by Jiaming Song, Chenlin Meng, and my PhD co-advisor, Stefano Ermon.
DDIM之所以更快，是因为它能跳过时间步长。
DDIM is faster because it's able to skip time steps.
所以它不是从500步到499步再到498步，而是能跳过所有这些步骤。
So instead of going from time step 500 to 499 to 498, it's able to skip all these time steps.
它能跳过很多步骤，因为它打破了马尔可夫假设。
And it's able to skip quite a bit, because it breaks the Markov assumption.
马尔可夫链只用于概率过程。
Markov chains are only used for probabilistic processes.
但DDIM实际上从这个采样过程中去除了所有的随机性，因此是确定性的。
But DDIM actually removes all the randomness from this sampling process, and is therefore deterministic.
它所做的，本质上就是预测最终输出的粗略草图。
And what it does, essentially, is it predicts a rough sketch of the final output.
然后用去噪过程对其进行细化。
And then it refines it with the denoising process.
那么让我们比较一下左边的DDPM，这是我们迄今为止一直在做的，和右边的DDIM。
So let's compare DDPM here on the left, which is what we've been doing so far, and DDIM here on the right.
是的，使用DDIM速度快很多。
Yes, it is much faster with DDIM.
在时间步19之后，你立即就能看到一个有形的结果。
You immediately see a buck there after time step 19.
我们还在继续使用DDPM。
And we're still going for DDPM.
我们还在继续。
We're still going.
而且这一直可以用DDPM达到500。
And this goes all the way up to 500 with DDPM, as you know.
好的，这里是实验课。
Great, so here's the lab.
很多设置看起来都一样。
A lot of the setup will look the same.
我只是在这里运行这个单元格，重新设置单位，我们的超参数。
So I'm just going to run this cell here, set up the unit again, our hyperparameters.
这是DDPM噪声计划。
Here's the DDPM noise schedule.
稍后我们会用它来和DDIM进行比较。
We'll use it to compare it to DDIM later.
现在我正在实例化模型。
Now I'm instantiating the model.
这里是用DDIM进行快速采样的地方。
And here's where fast sampling comes in with DDIM.
这是DDIM的功能。
So here's the function for DDIM.
可以查看论文了解细节，但这里实现了相应的缩放因子。
You can look at the paper for the details, but this implements that with its scaling factors.
然后我们在这里加载训练好的模型。
And then we load up our trained model here.
很酷的是，我们可以直接加载训练好的模型，使用DDIM或DDPM。
So what's cool is that we can actually just load up the trained model and use either DDIM or DDPM.
这都没关系。
It doesn't matter.
这只是训练后的采样过程。
This is just a sampling process after training.
这是使用DDIM的采样算法。
And this is the sampling algorithm using DDIM.
需要指出的是，这里涉及到一个步长。
And the only thing to call out is that there is a step size involved.
我们没有逐个时间步骤地进行。
We're not going through every single time step.
实际上我们在这里跳过了一些步骤。
We're actually skipping steps here.
这里的n是20。
And here is where n is 20.
所以这是500除以20。
So this is 500 over 20.
我们将在这里运行。
We'll run that here.
然后我们可以进行采样。
And then we can sample.
这速度快了很多。
That was much, much faster.
我几乎看不到那里。
I could barely even see that there.
现在正在合成GIF。
And now the GIF is just being composed.
我们会加快合成GIF的视频速度。
We'll speed up the video for the GIF.
好了！
All right.
这就是它的样子。
So here's what that looks like.
它能够瞬间变成这些游戏角色，速度非常快。
And it's very fast that it's able to instantly turn into these sprites.
现在用这种更快的采样方法，你并不总能得到和使用DDPM一样的质量。
Now with this faster sampling method, you don't always get the same level of quality as if you were to run DDPM.
但这些实际上看起来相当不错。
These actually do look quite good.
实际上，人们发现，用在这500步上训练的模型，例如，
Empirically, people have found that with a model trained on these 500 steps, for example,
如果你采样500步，DDPM的表现会更好。
DDPM will perform better if you sample for 500 steps.
但对于任何小于500步的数字，DDIM的表现会好得多。
But for any number under 500 steps, DDIM will do much better.
现在这里是相同的，但带有上下文模型。
And so now here's the same, but with a context model.
所以你可以加载那个上下文。
So you can load in that context.
太棒了！
Great.
这些只是随机的上下文。
So these are just random contexts here.
但你们也可以自己设置。
But you can set them yourselves as well.
它们是这样的。
And this is what they look like.
那么现在你们可能会问速度如何对比？
So now your question is probably, how does the speed compare?
我们可以加载原始的DDPM函数和采样算法。
So we can load up the original DDPM functions and sampling algorithm.
然后我们可以在这个Notebook中使用 timeit 进行比较。
And we can compare it using  timeit  in this notebook.
我们将比较DDIM和DDPM。
So we're going to compare DDIM with DDPM.
好了
All right.
看看这个速度提升。
Look at that speed up.
哇！
Wow.
试着在你们自己的Notebook中运行这些，看看结果如何。
So try running these in your own notebook and see what you get.